Guide to the British print advertisements, 1937-1963 and undated RL.11662
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
British print advertisements
1937-1963 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11662
3.0 Linear Feet
Collection consists of print advertisements and print advertising design sketches and renderings, as well as some finished advertisements mounted onto card stock. Also includes some promotional leaflets, manuals and catalogs. Advertisements were produced by an unidentified British agency (or agencies) for markets in Great Britain, Ireland, Canada, Australia and Switzerland; languages represented in advertising copy include English, French and German. Materials cover a wide range of consumer products such as airline travel, automobiles, clothing, cosmetics, food, garden supplies, laundry services, pharmaceutical goods, sewing and knitting supplies, shoes, radios, shoes, toys and watches; as well as industrial products and services including cleaning products, forges and foundries, hydraulic materials, and machines and machine supplies. Companies represented include ALMIN (Associated Light Metal Industries), British European Airways (precursor to British Airways), Fifty Shilling Tailors (Price Tailors Ltd.), Gre Solvent, Grossmith perfumers, James P. Corry, Pears, Society of Chemical Industry, Swissair and Wolseley Motors. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged into two series: Advertisements and Advertising Designs; Mounted Advertisements
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The British print advertisements collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2018.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Cosmetics Trade Samples and Sachet collection
Hart, Schaffner & Marx Advertising Service materials
J. Walter Thompson Company. Brouillard Communications vertical files
J. Walter Thompson Company. International Advertisements collection
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office Print advertisements
Collection Overview
Collection consists of print advertisements and print advertising design sketches and renderings, as well as some finished advertisements mounted onto card stock. Also includes some promotional leaflets, manuals and catalogs. Advertisements were produced by an unidentified British agency (or agencies) for markets in Great Britain, Ireland, Canada, Australia and Switzerland; languages represented in advertising copy include English, French and German. Materials cover a wide range of consumer products such as airline travel, automobiles, clothing, cosmetics, food, garden supplies, laundry services, pharmaceutical goods, sewing and knitting supplies, shoes, radios, shoes, toys and watches; as well as industrial products and services including cleaning products, forges and foundries, hydraulic materials, and machines and machine supplies. Companies represented include ALMIN (Associated Light Metal Industries), British European Airways (precursor to British Airways), Fifty Shilling Tailors (Price Tailors Ltd.), Gre Solvent, Grossmith perfumers, James P. Corry, Pears, Society of Chemical Industry, Swissair and Wolseley Motors. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising -- Great Britain -- History; Advertising -- Clothing and dress; Advertising -- Cosmetics; Advertising, Industrial; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; British Airways
- Advertisements and Advertising Designs, 1937-1963 and undated; 1
  - Booklets and catalogs, 1930s-1940s (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes: Gillot Electro-Steam Cooker; Newton & Bennett Trolley Boom Stabilisers; S.Wolf Handbook on Valve Refacing and Valve Seat Grinding; Spalding Nurseries catalog; Warco Tea Trolley; Warwick Aviation Children's paddle boat, rowing dinghy
  - ALMIN (Associated Light Metal Industries), undated (Box 1)
  - ALMIN (Associated Light Metal Industries), undated (Box 2)
  - Clarks of Retford (Laundry, dyeing), 1940s-1963 (Box 1)
  - Corry & Co. (Garden supplies, pesticides), undated (Box 1)
  - Diana Shoemakers, undated (Box 1)
  - Fifty Shilling Tailors (Price Tailors Ltd), approximately 1938 (Box 2)
  - Fifty Shilling Tailors (Price Tailors Ltd), Optrex eye lotion, 1937-1938 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Gre-Solvent (Cleaning products, industrial chemicals), undated (Box 1)
  - Grossmith (Perfume, cosmetics), undated (Box 1)
  - Grossmith (Perfume, cosmetics), undated (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1)
    Includes: Adminol (mineral tonic); Avia watches; Chamberlain & Jones Clothiers; Hiduminium (High Duty Alloys); L. Copley-Smith & Sons (yarns, knitting patterns); Yestamin (Dietary yeast)
  - Miscellaneous, 1938 and undated (Box 2)
    Includes: Hiduminium (High Duty Alloys); Lock-Joint Tiles; Magnuminium (Magnesium Castings & Products Ltd.); Pears soap
  - Optrex eye lotion, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Pears soap, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Perkin machines, undated (Box 1)
  - Strachans coachwork, undated (Box 2)
  - Swissair/BEA (British European Airways), 1959-1962 (Box 1)
  - Trufood (Baby food), undated (Box 1)
  - Portfolio cover embossed "SF" (Box 1)
- Mounted Advertisements, 1938-1960 and undated; 2
  - ALMIN (Associated Light Metal Industries), approximately 1948 (Box 2)
  - Avia watches, Society of Chemical Industry, 1947 and undated (Box 2)
  - Chamberlain & Jones Clothiers, Diana Shoemakers, L. Copley-Smith & Sons, undated (Box 2)
  - Grossmith (Ads for England, Australia, Canada, Ireland, Switzerland; in English, French, German), Yestamin, 1948-1949 and undated (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1949-1960s and undated (Box 2)
    Includes: Bon Fire lighters; Clarks of Retford; Granary Bread; Gre-Solvent; Morley's Ducina stockings; Newton & Bennett hydraulic fluid; Pears soap; Vidor radios; Wolseley 16/60 Viper; WTA; Yestamin
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2)
    Includes: Clarks of Retford; Hiduminium; Perkin machines; Renfrew Foundries; Warwick Aviation (aluminum goods)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2)
    Includes: Famel syrup (Optrex); Newton & Bennett hydraulic equipment; Optrex eye care; Trufood; also stationery letterhead designs for ALMIN, British Aviation Services, Southern Forge; Studio Irwin (photographers)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2)
    Includes: Hiduminium; L. Copley-Smith & Sons; Renfrew Foundries; Southern Forge; William Paul Ltd. (leather goods)
  - Pears soap, 1938 and undated (Box 2)